#### Alfred Shaheen

Foster City, California | 650-703-9945 | shaheenalfred48@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Github</u> | <u>Blog</u>

### **FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

As a Full-Stack Web Developer with a background in Restaurant Management and Tech Retail, I bring a unique blend of skills to the table. I'm a skilled collaborator and leader, with experience managing teams and training others. I'm also adept at managing customer relationships, which I believe is essential to the success of any business. I'm excited to bring these skills to a new opportunity and continue to grow as a developer.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Javascript (ES6), React, Ruby, Rails, SQL, PostgreSQL, Render, HTML, CSS, Git, RESTful Routing, Debugging tools (expry, byebug, react devtools, debugger, etc)

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

### Mardini's Restaurant - Github | Live Site | Demo

A full-stack web application for restaurant ordering that allows customers to place orders and view menu items.

- Built the application using Rails API backend and React front-end, and integrated session data management to allow customers to add items to their carts even if they sign up after adding items.
- Developed RESTful routing conventions to enable CRUD functionality for creating and editing menu items, and used CSS stylesheets and framer-motion to create an visually appealing and dynamic user interface.

# Cuisine Creations - Github | Live Site | Demo

A full-stack web application for creating, sharing, and discovering unique recipes that allows users to create and edit their own recipes, as well as add ingredients, steps, and measurements.

- Implemented user authentication and authorization using Ruby on Rails for the backend and React for the frontend to allow users to create and edit their own recipes.
- Designed the application with RESTful routing conventions and CRUD functionality, and used CSS to create a visually appealing and user-friendly interface.

## Semi-Addicting Games - Github | Live Site | Demo

A single-page web application that combines two popular games, tic-tac-toe and hangman, using React.

- Integrated React-router-dom, styled-components, and framer-motion to create a visually appealing and user-friendly interface.
- Challenged with integrating both games into a single-page application while maintaining a seamless user experience, and utilized React-router-dom to manage game state and transitions between pages.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Best Buy | Mobile Specialist**

San Carlos, CA

May 2017 - June 2019

- Demonstrated exceptional sales skills, achieving an average of \$1000 in sales per day and consistently exceeding monthly sales targets by 10%.
- Utilized strong product knowledge to provide customers with customized recommendations, resulting in a 95% customer satisfaction rate.
- Processed transactions and handled cash, credit, and check payments with 100% accuracy and efficiency, processing an average of 30 transactions per day.
- Sustained up-to-date knowledge of wireless products, accessories, pricing plans and service features.

### Mardini's Deli and Cafe | Operations Manager

Menlo Park, CA

September 2012 - June 2019

- Supervised a team of 5 employees, serving an average of 300 customers daily and generating a weekly revenue of \$10,000
- Efficiently managed a weekly inventory budget of \$5,000, ensuring high-quality products for customers...
- Maintained a high level of customer satisfaction by promptly resolving any complaints regarding food quality, service, or accommodations
- Review work procedures and operational problems to determine ways to improve service, performance, or safety.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Flatiron School**

Certified Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

October 2022 - January 2023

### College of San Mateo

Completed coursework in Math and Physics

January 2017 - May 2019